Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Writings and Speeches, 1912-2000 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Writings and Speeches 1912-2000 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
30 linear feet Extent: 20,000 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is the largest enduring advertising agency in the United States. The Information Center of the New York Office began a collection of writings and speeches by former JWT executives. Later, scrapbooks and binders of speeches by Stanley Resor and Arno Johnson and Norman Strouse were added, and the Information Center expanded its activities to routinely collect texts of speeches given by current JWT staff. After the transfer of the JWT Archives to Duke University, additions continued to be received and interfiled. The J. Walter Thompson Company Writings and Speeches collection spans 1912 through 2000 and includes primarily printed texts of speeches given by advertising executives employed at the J. Walter Thompson Company. Also included to a lesser extent are clippings or reprints of articles, reports, and white papers, along with some books written in whole or in part by JWT staff. Topics include general trends in advertising and marketing, specific themes related to JWT's policies and philosophies, year-end reports, specific marketing strategies. Notable individuals represented include Rena Bartos, Charlotte Beers, Jeremy Bullmore, Nariman Dhalla, Arno Johnson, Don Johnston, Denis Lanigan, Burt Manning, Vergil Reed, Stanley Resor, Dan Seymour, Norman H. Strouse, and James Webb Young.
RL.00762
Language: Material in English, German, and French
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Materials are closed to non-JWT staff for 15 years from the date of creation.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Writings and Speeches were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as transfers from 1987 through 2002. Additions are regularly received.
Collection Overview
The J. Walter Thompson Company Writings and Speeches collection spans 1912 through 2000 and includes primarily printed texts of speeches given by advertising executives employed at the J. Walter Thompson Company. Also included to a lesser extent are clippings or reprints of articles, reports, and white papers, along with some books written in whole or in part by JWT staff. Topics include general trends in advertising and marketing, specific themes related to JWT's policies and philosophies, year-end reports, specific marketing strategies. Notable individuals represented include Rena Bartos, Charlotte Beers, Jeremy Bullmore, Nariman Dhalla, Arno Johnson, Don Johnston, Denis Lanigan, Burt Manning, Vergil Reed, Stanley Resor, Dan Seymour, Norman H. Strouse, and James Webb Young. The collection was originally started by the Information Center of JWT New York Office.
Collection Arrangement
Collection is arranged alphabetically by last name; therein materials are arranged chronologically. At the end of the named listing, there are grouped writings and speeches involving multiple authors; materials where authorship cannot be attributed; and writings that comprised the Creative Forum in the 1960s.
Subject Headings
J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company -- History; J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office; Bartos, Rena; Beers, Charlotte; Bullmore, J. J. D.; Dhalla, Nariman K.; Johnson, Arno H. (Arno Hallock), 1901-; Johnston, Don, 1927-; Lanigan, Denis, 1926-; Manning, Burt; Reed, Vergil D. (Vergil Daniel), b. 1896; Resor, Stanley Burnet, 1879-1962; Seymour, Dan, 1915-1982; Strouse, Norman H.; Young, James Webb, 1886-; J. Walter Thompson Company -- Employees; Advertising -- History; Advertising agencies -- History; Advertising executives; Marketing -- United States; Marketing -- United States -- Case studies; Speeches, addresses, etc., American; Speeches; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Open Files, 1912-1993 and undated
  - Achenbaum, Alvin, (3 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1968. Speech. Magic Ingredient in New Product Development (Box 1)
    - 1971. Speech. Does Advertising Manipulate Consumer Behavior (Statement in behalf of Joint ANA/AAAA Committee before FTC, 2 versions) (Box 1)
    - 1971. Article. Hope and the Opportunity (Box 1)
    - 1971. Speech. Research's New Responsibility in a Consumerist Environment (Box 1)
    - 1972. Article. Advertising Doesn't Manipulate Consumers (Box 1)
    - 1972. Other writing. Market Testing...(chapter for Marketing Handbook, ed. R. Ferber) (Box 1)
    - 1973. Speech. How Research Can Help in the Strategic Positioning of a Brand (Box 1)
    - 1973. Article. How Research Can Work to Help Position a Brand (Box 1)
    - 1973. Speech. Is Advertising Manipulating the Consumer (Box 1)
    - 1973. Speech. Segmenting Markets: Recrowning the Consumer King (Box 1)
    - 1973. Speech. Today's Consumer: Is Advertising Manipulating Her? (Box 1)
    - 1977. Article. Achenbaum Tells about Picking an Agency--Toyota, Datsun Style (Box 1)
    - 1977. Article. GRP's Can't Measure Effectiveness (Box 1)
    - 1979. Article. Impending Media Crisis (Box 1)
  - Adams, Michael
    - 1991. Speech. Diamonds in the '90s (Box 1)
  - Agnew, Jim
    - Undated. Speech. J. Walter West--Winds of Change (Box 1)
  - Andler, Donald A.
    - 1966. Article. Some Magazines are Best Buy in Off-Season (Box 1)
  - Antonowsky, Marvin
    - 1966. Article. New of Spot TV Markets (Box 1)
    - 1967-1968. Article. Media Myths (series in Media Decisions) (Box 1)
    - 1968-1969. Article. Media Math (series in Media Decisions) (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Donald B., Jr., (2 folders)
    - 1963. Speech. Measured Advertising Results--Revisited (Box 1)
    - 1970. Speech. Needed: A New Consumer Look at Marketing (Box 1)
    - 1973. Speech. New Products: The Advertising Agency's Contributions and Problems (Box 1)
    - 1975. Article. Change in the Market Place: An Analysis of the Recent Changes in Consumer Behavior and the Events and Attitudes Underlying Them (co-author: Garth Hallbert) (Box 1)
    - 1975. Speech. Consumers New Reality: An Analysis of Changes in the Market Place (speech, article) (Box 1)
    - 1975. Article. Is Comparison Advertising Really Better? (Box 1)
    - 1975. Article. Stimulus and Response: There is No Such Thing as a Typical Consumer (Box 1)
    - 1975-1976. Speech. Use and Abuse of Survey Research in Advertising Regulation (speech, article) (Box 1)
    - 1976. Article. TV Violence: In the Eyes of the Beholders (printed adaptation of speech) (Box 1)
    - 1977. Article. Three Research Pitfalls in Fighting FTC Complaints (Box 1)
    - 1978. Speech. Is There a Crisis in Branding in the U.S.? (Box 1)
  - Ashford, Jim
    - Circa 1990. Speech. Murphy's Law (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Leigh
    - 1967. Article. Public Relations in Action (Box 1)
  - Aubrey, Stever
    - 1968. Speech. Advertising Awards Day (draft) (Box 1)
    - 1970. Speech. Marketing Policies in Times of Restricted Gas Supply (Box 1)
  - Auer, Renee, (2 folders)
    - 1985-1986. Other writing. Profile of Canada (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Ray T.
    - 1960. Article. Big Challenge in Marketing in the '60s (Am. Egg and Poultry Review) (Box 1)
    - 1960. Speech. Dynamics of Food Distribution: A History of 100 Years of Evolution in Grocery Store Distribution in America (Box 1)
    - 1960. Speech. Intro. to Remarks for Panel on New Dimensions in Manufacturer-Distributor Relations (Box 1)
    - 1960. Speech. State of Industry (USWGA Mtg., Dallas) (Box 1)
  - Barber, B.J.
    - 1993. Other writing. Understanding Quebec (Box 1)
  - Barnard, Philip
    - 1992. Article. New Directions in World Research (Box 1)
  - Barnum, H.J. (Box 2)
    - 1974. Speech. Mass Media and Health Communications (Box 2)
  - Bartolon, Dan G.
    - 1984. Speech. JWT Managing the Agency (Box 2)
  - Bartos, Rena, (1-25 of 39 folders)
    - 1973. Speech. Research, Creativity, and Tunnel Vision (Box 2)
    - 1973. Speech. Target is Moving (Box 2)
    - 1973. Speech. Why a Full-Service Agency? (Box 2)
    - 1973. Speech. Women's Place (and Yours) (Box 2)
    - 1973. Speech. Working Women: The Invisible Consumer Travel Market (Box 2)
    - 1973-1998. Article. Miscellaneous brief articles (Box 2)
    - 1974. Article. Future of the Advertising Agency Research Function (Box 2)
    - 1974. Speech. Who Pipes, Who Pays, Who Calls the Tune? (Box 2)
    - 1974-1979. Other writing. Moving Target, and related articles (Box 2)
    - 1975. Speech. Advertising and the Economy (Box 2)
    - 1975. Speech. Consumer View of Advertising (Box 2)
    - 1975. Speech. Moving Target (Box 2)
    - 1976. Other writing. Advertising and Consumers (Box 2)
    - 1976. Speech. Opportunities and How to Capitalize on Them (Box 2)
    - 1976. Speech. Working Woman Audience: The Moving Target (Box 2)
    - 1977. Other writing. Founding Fathers of Advertising Research (Box 2)
    - 1978. Speech. Stereotypes, Assumtions, and the Reality Gap (Box 2)
    - 1978. Article. Target is Moving: The Changing Bank Customer (Box 2)
    - 1978. Article. What Every Marketer Should Know about Women (Box 2)
    - 1979. Article. Exploring Mysterious Markets (Box 2)
    - 1980. Speech. Do We Really Have to Make Them Mad to Sell Them? (Box 2)
    - 1980. Article. Over 49: The Invisible Consumer Market (Box 2)
    - 1981. Article. Ads that Irritate May Erode Trust in Advertised Brands (Box 2)
    - 1981. Article. Beyond the Cookie Cutters (Box 2)
    - 1981. Speech. Beyond the Rocking Chair (Box 2)
  - Bartos, Rena (continued), (26-39 of 39 folders) (Box 3)
    - 1982. Speech. Demographics of Older Shoppers and 1-2 Person Households (Box 3)
    - 1982. Article. Women and Travel (Box 3)
    - 1982. Article. Women's Market for Big-Ticket Items (Box 3)
    - 1983. Speech. Moving Target: Changing Demographics (Box 3)
    - 1983. Article. Women and Advertising (Box 3)
    - 1984. Speech. Targeting the Top (Box 3)
    - 1985. Speech. Qualitative Research: What It is and Where It Came from (speech and 2 published versions) (Box 3)
    - 1985-1986. Speech. Facts of Life (Box 3)
    - 1986. Speech. Challenging Our Assumptions (Box 3)
    - 1986. Speech. Over 49: The Invisible Consumer Market (Box 3)
    - 1986. Article. Qualitative Research (Box 3)
    - 1988. Speech. Marketing to Women around the World (Box 3)
    - Undated. Speech. Demographic Questions (Box 3)
    - Undated. Other writing. Do-It-Yourself Workbook for Developing a Moving Target Presentation (handbook) (Box 3)
  - Bathon, Greg
    - 1974. Speech. Consumer Behavior in Brazil (Box 3)
    - 1978. Speech. Managing a JWT Office for Performance & Profit (Box 3)
  - Baumwoll, Joel P., (10 folders)
    - 1974. Speech. Segmentation Research: The Baker vs. the Cooker Maker (speech, article) (Box 3)
    - 1975. Article. Change in the Market Place: An Analysis of the Recent Changes is Consumer Behavior and the Events and Attitudes Underlying Them (co-author: Garth Hallbert) (Box 3)
    - 1975. Article. Is comparison Advertising Really Better? (Box 3)
    - 1975. Article. Stimulus and Response: There is No Such Thing as a Typical Consumer (Box 3)
    - 1975-1976. Speech. Consumers New Reality: An Analysis of Changes in the Market Place (speech, article) (Box 3)
    - 1976. Article. TV Violence: In the Eyes of the Beholders (printed adaptation of speech) (Box 3)
    - 1976. Speech. Use and Abuse of Survey Research in Advertising Regulation (speech, article) (Box 3)
    - 1977. Speech. Recall Testing Can Be Dangerous to Your Product's Health (Box 3)
    - 1977. Article. Three Research Pitfalls in Fighting FTC Complaints (Box 3)
    - 1978. Speech. Is There a Crisis in Branding in the U.S.? (Box 3)
  - Baxter, Loy J.
    - 1965. Speech. 100th Anniversary of Advertising (Box 3)
    - 1965. Speech. Public Relations--Publicity (Box 3)
    - 1968. Speech. Opening Remarks (speech to U.S. Marine Corps) (Box 3)
    - 1968. Speech. Untitled (speech to Indiana University graduating seniors) (Box 3)
    - 1968. Article. Uses of the On-Location Portrait (Box 3)
    - 1969. Speech. Untitled (speech to Army Chaplains) (Box 3)
  - Beatson, Ronald (Box 4)
    - 1983. Speech. MARS: Defence of Advertising Working Party (Box 4)
    - 1984. Speech. Image of Advertising in Europe (Box 4)
  - Beckerman, Jerrold
    - 1974. Speech. Speech given to AMA (Box 4)
  - Beers, Charlotte, (19 folders)
    - 1973. Speech. Speech given to AMA (Box 4)
    - 1974. Speech. How to Get a Better Return on Your Advertising Investment (Box 4)
    - 1974. Speech. New York Show (Box 4)
    - 1975. Speech. Account Management (Box 4)
    - 1975. Speech. American Management Association (Box 4)
    - 1975. Speech. How to Know If a Client is Really Happy (Box 4)
    - 1975. Speech. Productivity: The New Measure of an Agency (Box 4)
    - 1975. Speech. Pursuit of Productivity (Box 4)
    - 1976. Speech. Advertising Agency of the Future (Box 4)
    - 1976. Speech. Communications and Lifestyles (Box 4)
    - 1976. Speech. Getting Inside the Consumer's Head (Box 4)
    - 1976. Speech. What Alice Saw in the Looking Glass (Box 4)
    - 1977. Speech. Norman Strouse Seminar (Box 4)
    - 1977. Speech. North American Seminar (Box 4)
    - 1977. Speech. What Do You Do for a Living? (Box 4)
    - 1977. Speech. Women's Lifestyles (Box 4)
    - 1978. Other writing. New Business Issues and Techniques (handbook) (Box 4)
    - 1978. Speech. Job Survival Skills for Women in Management Positions (Box 4)
    - 1978. Speech. Tomorrow's Managers (Box 4)
  - Berent, Paul Howard
    - 1965. Speech. What is the Market Researcher Doing in an Advertising Agency? (Box 4)
    - 1971. Speech. Market Research on a Multi-Country Basis (Box 4)
  - Bergamo, Nestor
    - Undated. Speech. Entrepreneur in the Future of the Brazilian Economy (Box 4)
  - Bernhardt, Jack
    - 1967. Other writing. What the Creative Person Should Expect from the Account Man--And Vice Versa (Creative Forum paper #15) (Box 4)
    - 1969. Speech. How Advertising Can Sirve (sic) You (Box 4)
  - Black, George
    - 1983. Speech. Our Experience with Multi-National Brands, Their Communication Strategies and Systems (Box 4)
  - Black, Harry (?)
    - 1979. Other writing. Effective Reach: From Theory to Practice (JWT Media Department Report) (Box 4)
  - Black, Kenneth
    - 1979. Speech. How Advertising Works (Box 4)
  - Blair, Milton J.
    - 1935. Speech. Speculative Preparation of Plans, Copy or Art Work in the Solicitation of Business (Box 4)
    - 1936. Speech. Changes in the American Fruit Basket during the Last Thirty-Five Years (Box 4)
  - Bonner, Robert
    - 1977. Speech. Challenge of Rapid Change (Box 4)
  - Baren, Wallace
    - 1942-1945. Article. Wally's Wagon (brief clippings from This Week) (Box 4)
  - Boyle, Joseph
    - 1955. Speech. Integration of a Public Relations-Publicity Department within an Agency (Box 4)
  - Braley, Berton
    - 1940s. Other writing. Miscellaneous Poetry (printed in This Week) (Box 4)
  - Brand, Jonathan
    - 1975. Article. Untitled (Box 4)
  - Brigandi, George
    - Circa 1985. Speech. Study of the Changing Structure of the Retail Food Market (Box 4)
  - Brinckerhoff, John H.
    - 1973. Article. Consumer Agency vs. the Specialized Agency: Which is the Best for Medical Advertising? (Box 4)
  - Broderick, Gerry
    - 1983. Speech. JWT--Who is it? (Box 4)
  - Brouillard, Joseph
    - 1973. Speech. Corporate Communications in the European Business Community (Box 4)
    - 1973. Article. Television: The Workhorse for Corporate Advertisers (Box 4)
    - 1978. Article. Larger Picture in Corporate Advertising (Box 4)
    - 1979. Speech. Corporate Communications: Opportunities for Growth (Box 4)
  - Brown, Steve
    - 1991. Speech. JWT Lifestages (Box 4)
  - Buchanan, Robert E. (Buck), (5 folders)
    - 1976. Speech. Using Broadcast Syndication to Reach Your Market (Box 4)
    - 1981. Speech. New Media (speech on cable, satellite transmission, etc.) (Box 4)
    - 1981. Article. Tis the Season (Box 4)
    - 1985. Speech. Changing U.S. Media Scene--Does It Have Any Meaning for Latin America (Box 4)
    - 1985. Speech. Media Requirements of Multinational Clients (Box 4)
  - Buckley, Joseph C.
    - 1962. Other writing. Oil Filter Replacement Market on Farms (internal report) (Box 4)
  - Bullmore, Jeremy, (11 folders) (Box 5)
    - 1972. Speech. Consumer Has a Mind as well as a Stomach (Box 5)
    - 1973. Speech. Speech given at ICA conference (Box 5)
    - 1977. Speech. British Admen Know People Better Than Politicians (Box 5)
    - 1978. Speech. Ten Tried and Trusted Methods of Getting the Least from Your Advertising Agency (Box 5)
    - 1978. Speech. What Jim Young Said--And What He Didn't Say (Box 5)
    - 1979. Article. Has Advertising Lost its Way? (Box 5)
    - 1979. Speech. Persuasion--What Can We Learn from the Politicians and What Can They Learn from Us? (Box 5)
    - 1982. Other writing. Close-Up (report on Thompson London) (Box 5)
    - 1983. Other writing. Advertising Association Handbook (Box 5)
    - 1983. Speech. Close-Up-1983 (speech on Thompson London) (Box 5)
    - 1984. Speech. Creative Marketplace--Some Things We Have Learned (Box 5)
    - 1984. Speech. What We Have Learned (Box 5)
    - 1984. Speech. What We Have Learned about Creative Advertising (Box 5)
    - 1985. Speech. Archimedes and the Efficacy of Prayer: Some Thoughts on How We Think of Things and Put Them to the Test (Box 5)
    - 1985. Article. Brand and Its Image Revisited (Box 5)
    - 1987. Other writing. Miscellaneous writing (Box 5)
  - Burns, Ron
    - 1993. Speech. Leadership through Innovation (Box 5)
  - Campbell-Harris, Davis
    - 1982. Speech. Happy Guy Fawkes Day (Box 5)
    - 1984. Other writing. Some Things We Believe about JWT People (excerpt) (Box 5)
  - Cannonero, Lea
    - 1975. Speech. Importance of Communication (Box 5)
    - 1975. Speech. Secretary's Role in Working with People (Box 5)
    - 1975. Speech. Steps in Problem Solving (Box 5)
  - Carney, Otis
    - 1952. Speech. Creating the TV Commercial (Box 5)
  - Carroll, Carroll
    - Circa 1964. Other writing. Fiscal Century (poetry) (Box 5)
    - 1965. Article. Hello All You Folks Out There in Radioland Revisited (Box 5)
    - Circa 1966. Speech. Raspberry for the Teacher (Box 5)
    - 1969. Article. How to Start a Search for Success in the World's Largest Ad Agency (from Variety) (Box 5)
    - 1976. Article. And Now a Word From... (from Variety) (Box 5)
    - 1976. Article. Letter to Editor, MAC/Western Advertising News (concerns anniversary issue on JWT) (Box 5)
    - 1976. Article. They Still Love Me in Altoon, Writes Bruns, a Man Idolized (from Variety) (Box 5)
    - 1976. Article. Real Kraftsman (from Television/Radio Age) (Box 5)
    - 1978. Interview. RAB interview about radio (Box 5)
    - Undated. Article. How Creative Should a Radio Commercial Be--And How? (draft and edited version) (Box 5)
    - Undated. Article. Need for Sound Involvement (Box 5)
  - Casseres, Aminta
    - 1926. Article. Agencies Prefer Men! (from Printer's Ink) (Box 5)
  - Chaiet, Alan
    - 1981. Article. When is a GRP Not a GRP? (Box 5)
    - 1982. Article. Prune Principle of Advertising Exposure (Box 5)
  - Charlton, Fred
    - Undated. Article. How Can We Improve Frozen Food Retailing? (Box 5)
  - Checkman, Lee
    - 1981. Article. Virgin Respondents are Hard to Find (Box 5)
  - Cherington, Paul T.
    - 1923. Article. Federal Legislation concerning the Branding of Fabrics (Box 5)
    - 1923. Speech. Twentieth Century Marketing (summary of speech) (Box 5)
    - 1924. Article. Some Commercial aspects of Styles and Fashions in the Clothing and Textile Industries (from Harvard Business Review) (Box 5)
    - 1926. Speech. Place of Advertising in Church Work (Box 5)
    - 1926. Article. What Producers Can Do to Maintain Prices (Box 5)
    - 1928. Article. Obligations of Business Research Advertising and Selling (Box 5)
    - 1928. Article. Shifting Sands of Distribution (Box 5)
    - 1928. Article. Unadvertised Medicine (Box 5)
    - 1930. Article. Can Commercial Research Methods Be applied to the Distribution of Securities (Box 5)
    - 1928. Article. Why the Legal Profession Needs Advertising (Box 5)
    - 1930. Article. What Social Statistics Tell Us about Markets (Box 5)
    - 1939. Speech. Frontiers and Pioneering (Box 5)
    - 1939. Article. Small Retailer (from Harvard Business Review) (Box 5)
    - 1940. Article. How Capitalism Can Get its Second Wind (Box 5)
  - Chi, Joyce Saxon
    - 1982. Speech. Untitled (Box 5)
  - Christianson, Elin B.
    - 1965. Article. Automation and Libraries (Box 5)
    - 1966. Article. Musings on Minneapolis (Box 5)
    - 1968. Article. Variation of Editorial Material in Periodicals Indexed in Readers' Guide (Box 5)
  - Churchill, Mary
    - 1988. Speech. Communicating the JWT Story (Box 5)
    - 1988. Speech. Momentum (Box 5)
  - Ciuti, Ezio (Box 6)
    - 1984. Speech. Analysis of McCann-Erickson (Box 6)
  - Clark, Earl
    - 1928. Speech. Finance (outline of speech) (Box 6)
    - 1929. Speech. Profits of an Advertising Agency (Box 6)
    - 1932. Speech. Lying and Stealing (Box 6)
    - 1933. Other writing. On legal aspects of advertising (with comments from Slaughter & May, legal counsel for JWT London) (Box 6)
  - Clark, Harry, (3 folders)
    - 1974. Speech. Speech given at IAA meeting (Box 6)
    - 1985. Other writing. Some Things We Have Learned About Starting New Agencies (report) (Box 6)
    - 1986. Speech. David Ogilvy, Robert Browning and Other Voices I Have Heard (speech for Princeton group, 2 versions) (Box 6)
    - 1987. Article. Consumer and Corporate Values: Yet Another View on Global Marketing (Box 6)
    - 1994. Speech. JWT's Clark Speaks at International Advertising Meeting (speech on European agency/advertiser financial relationship) (Box 6)
  - Clauson, A.W. (Tom)
    - 1971. Speech. Toward an Arithmetic of Quality (Box 6)
  - Clements, George, (1-20 of 35 folders)
    - 1979. Speech. James Webb Young Seminar (Box 6)
    - 1980. Article. In Testing Advertising Computers May Lead You Astray (Box 6)
    - 1980. Article. Liking--A New Scale for Measuring the Response of Consumers (Box 6)
    - 1981. Article. Advertising Testing through to 2001 (Box 6)
    - 1981. Speech. Role of Financial Advertising in Investor Relations (Box 6)
    - 1982. Article. Invisible Consumers (Box 6)
    - 1982. Speech. Relationship of Advertising Expenditure Levels to Media Costs in Canada and the United States; or, An Exploration into the World of Darkness (Box 6)
    - 1983. Article. Business Needs to Plan Now to Offset Future Static Markets (Box 6)
    - 1983. Speech. We Are What We Eat (Box 6)
    - 1983. Speech. Women are Human, Too. (Box 6)
    - 1984. Speech. Pacific isn't Terrific? (Box 6)
    - 1984-1986. Speech. Thinking About the Ads (Box 6)
    - 1985. Speech. Asia/Pacific: A Dipstick View of the Region (Box 6)
    - 1985. Speech. Creativity: Nice or Necessary? (Box 6)
    - 1985. Article. Pacific isn't Terrific? (Box 6)
    - 1985. Speech. Some Thoughts About Advertising Research (Box 6)
    - 1985. Other writing. T-Plan and Planning Cycle (handbook) (Box 6)
    - 1985-1991. Speech. Brand Personality (Box 6)
    - 1987. Speech. Communications and the Lawyer (Box 6)
    - 1987. Speech. Devising the Best Strategy (Box 6)